Let's talk about work performance data,
information, and reports.
So work performance data, when we are
doing the work of the project,
we are in the executing process group,
doing the work of the project.
So that's where we create data.
Our team is working to create the
deliverables of the project.
All right.
So I want you to think of work
performance.
performance data as raw observations and
measurements taken during executing.
As we're doing the work of the project,
our team is doing the work of the project,
creating the deliverables.
These are our actuals, like number of
change requests, number of validation
cycles, actual start dates, actual finish
dates, actual durations, actual costs.
Okay, so these are the things.
that are considered data, actuals.
So just keep that in mind.
So an example that we have on this second
slide, task A finished June 1st.
We've spent 10,000.
We would list the number of change requests
we've received at this point in time.
Okay, that is data, data.
Now, work performance
data will feed into every
controlling process, monitoring
and controlling process.
Because of monitoring and controlling,
we're comparing our plan, our baselines,
scope, schedule, cost baselines,
to the data.
What's actually happening?
We're looking for variance.
Our plan, which includes our baselines,
is what was agreed upon.
We have to compare to what is actually
being done.
Again, we're looking for variance.
So that comparison between our plan,
which in the baselines, compared to data,
actuals, will give us what is called work
performance information, progress,
progress, and this will be for every
knowledge area.
Scope, schedule, cost, quality,
on down.
all right so we compare the data to the
plan what was agreed upon to figure out
our progress so the example for this
information progress task a finished a
month late notice the difference this is
the progress we're a month late whereas up
here just data this is when it
finished comparing data what
actually happened to to the
plan baselines give us progress.
Oh, we are a month late with task A.
We are 20,000 over budget.
Up here, data was just saying we've spent
10,000.
That's our actual cost.
That tells us nothing
really until we compare it
to what was agreed upon
in our plan, our baselines.
We're 20,000 over.
So our progress will give us status of our
deliverables what how we are progressing
with our project all the progress all the
work performance information that we just
discussed that we will create comes out of
every single monitoring and controlling
process what's the progress with the scope
the schedule the cost quality etc is all
compiled into work performance reports
Now, reports go out to stakeholders.
Reports are used to raise awareness,
take action, and make decisions.
That's really important, so make sure to
write that down somewhere, okay?
Reports go out to stakeholders.
It is with work performance reports that
we, we, because we're sending out the
reports, we will raise awareness, take
action and make decisions based on reports.
Reports are what's happening with every
aspect of the project.
We're putting all the
progress together, all that work
performance information
together to create those reports.
Again, if you look at this third
bullet, because I've mentioned
everything else already,
reports go out to stakeholders.
So, yep, they'll be
communicated to the stakeholders
because this is how
we will raise awareness.
The reports are used to make.
decisions take action all right so types
of reports and we'll talk about these in
the upcoming lesson status reports how the
project currently stands okay status they
can be in the form of charts graphs tables
all right so there are all kinds of
different ways reports can be depicted in
agile their information radiators all
right showing what's happening with every
aspect of the project like con bond boards
burn up burn down charts those are
discussed in more detail on upcoming
lessons as well so hang in there for more
information